[Kevin Flynn] The Grid.
A digital frontier.
A world beyond the screen
as real as our own.
I can picture it.
Clusters of information
rising like cities.
Programs as complex
as you and me.
In just a few years,
we're gonna be able
to enter this world.
And a few years after that,
well, this world
will come into ours.
Intelligent life
from inside the machine.
I, for one,
can't wait to meet it.
Our lead story,
Encom CEO and video game icon
Kevin Flynn has disappeared.
He was best known
for designing Tron
and Space Paranoids,
the best-selling video games
in history.
The company that started
at Kevin Flynn's arcade
in the 1980s
has faced years
of corporate turmoil.
Can it find its way to
the victory screen once again?
It's a sister-act for Encom.
Eve and Tess Kim
take the reins
of the massive tech company
after Sam Flynn resigns
for personal reasons.
[reporter 1] Encom's rebound
under the Kim sisters'
leadership
has competitors
rushing to respond.
Software giant
Dillinger Systems
appoints its new CEO,
Julian Dillinger,
who vows to restore
his grandfather's legacy.
The race between Encom
and Dillinger Systems heats up
as new CEOs Julian Dillinger
and the Kim sisters
square off.
[Tess] Here at Encom,
we believe the beauty of AI
is not the ability to build
smarter weapons
but to uplift humanity,
feed the hungry,
cure the sick,
educate the world.
[reporter 2] Rival CEOs
Julian Dillinger and Eve Kim
have gone quiet
in recent months,
raising speculation
the two companies
are very close
to a substantial
technological breakthrough.
[Robin Roberts]
One that has the potential
to transform humanity
in ways we have
never seen before.
The future may well lie
in the hands
of whoever gets there first.
[beeping]
[♪ electronic music playing]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[all grunting, groaning]
[groaning, grunting]
[inhales deeply, panting]
[whirring]
[breathing heavily]
[device whirring]
[disembodied voice] Welcome.
Who are you?
I am your creator.
And who am I?
[inhales]
Mmm.
Not "who." What.
You are Dillinger Systems
security software.
Program name, Ares.
Defender of the Grid.
You are Master Control.
Ares.
I am Master Control.
[♪ electronic music playing]
[device whirring, beeps]
So, you made it.
I had a feeling
that you would.
I always dreamed that
we would do this together.
I'll admit,
not exactly like this.
But I'm glad you're here.
I'm really glad.
And, Evie,
remember I'm still here.
Even if you can't see me.
I love you.
-[person] Oh, my God. Um, Eve.
-[door opens]
I'm not sure you
actually told me
we'd be stealing energy
from the power grid.
Wow. So this is where
she kept coming back to, huh?
To be this disconnected
from the world?
[chuckles]
That is dedication, my friend.
Wow.
It looks like your sister
had a little crush.
Yeah. She was so sure
Flynn left us the answer.
Like on a floppy disk?
Poor Flynn lived
before the cloud, huh?
Hey, are you still
gonna be doing
CEO-type stuff
while we're out here?
You know, like,
earnings calls,
and the launch
of Panic City and stuff.
Let's just get this done.
Dude, I can make breakfast
burritos right here.
Hell yeah.
[exhales]
This is for you, Tess.
[beeps]
[person] Members of the board,
for over 40 years,
my family at Dillinger Systems
has battled Encom
for control of the future.
You put me in charge
of the company
to ensure our victory.
Today...
[chuckling] I make it so.
Imagine if all our
digital prowess
wasn't just digital.
What if anything we could
dream in the machine
could become a reality here?
What if we could
build the bridge
between two previously
walled-off worlds?
So much talk of AI
in big tech today.
Virtual worlds,
what are they gonna look like?
When will we get there?
Well, folks.
We're not going there.
They are coming here.
[announcer 1 on PA] Attention,
please put on
your safety glasses now.
[alarm bell ringing]
[announcer 2 on PA]
Laser systems activated.
Power fluctuations
are nominal.
[announcer 1]
Warning, stand clear.
[announcer 2] Outputting
from Dillinger Systems server.
[lasers whirring]
[announcer 3] Raw material
inflow initiated.
[electricity pulsating,
crackling]
[♪ electronic music playing]
[inhales, exhales]
[announcer 2]
T-minus ten, nine,
eight, seven,
six, five,
four, three,
two, one...
Transfer complete.
I present
the Dillinger Systems
Amphibious
Rapid-response Tank.
The DART.
Digitally modeled
inside our server,
output using our patented
laser technology.
There's an M1 rifle gun,
two M240 machine guns.
It's got a top speed of
75 miles per hour.
Durability, you find a wall,
this thing is gonna
drive through it.
This is full-scale war,
five minutes' notice.
So, if we can create
the hardware of the future,
then why not
the soldier to operate it?
[♪ ominous music playing]
[all gasp]
Ladies and gentlemen,
I would like you to meet Ares.
This is the most sophisticated
security program ever written.
Do you wanna shake his hand?
Go ahead. He doesn't bite.
Ares has billions of lines
of code unique to him.
[board member] Is it alive?
[Julian] That depends
on your definition, Stuart.
[board members murmuring]
[Julian] Because unlike you,
he's biblically strong,
lightning fast,
and supremely intelligent.
He is fully proprietary
and 100% expendable.
Ares is the ultimate soldier.
He needs no food, no water,
sheds no blood.
And if, by some miracle,
he is struck down
on the battlefield,
I will simply
make you another.
[thunder rumbling]
[General] With all that
sophisticated code,
what makes you think
you can contain it?
I can assure you, General,
the most advanced
fail-safe mechanisms
and restriction protocols
are in place.
Ares is predictable,
controllable
and fully aligned.
Southerly front
with isentropic lift,
turning cyclonic.
Predicted precipitation:
2.6 inches.
I hope that you brought
your umbrellas.
[all chuckling]
I have to hand it to you,
Julian.
You promised a big win
and this is even bigger
than any of us
could've imagined.
-[applause]
-[Julian] Thank you.
My grandfather started
Dillinger Corporation
long before anybody heard
the term "cybersecurity."
Military AI is the future.
The question is not whether
the car should be built.
The car is...
being built right now.
The question is...
who's holding the keys?
[engines revving]
[fireflies buzzing]
[sighs] That was
quite some parlor trick.
-Time?
-Forty-four seconds.
"I hope you
brought your umbrellas."
Oh, was that in the script,
or was he just
having a moment?
Elisabeth Dillinger,
eldest daughter of founder
Edward Dillinger, deceased.
Longtime CEO during a
relatively unremarkable period
of corporate history
before being superseded
by your only son.
It's a pleasure.
Unremarkable?
Market share was up 12%
during my tenure.
That's hardly...
And anyway, we don't say
it "superseded," we...
[sighs]
...we call it "giving birth."
Of course.
[beeping]
[distorted] It's an honor
to meet my creator's creator.
Oh, well, here we go.
-[armor beeping]
-[groaning]
[Elisabeth] I noticed
you left out the part
where you can't seem to keep
this thing of yours alive
-for more than 25 minutes.
-Twenty-nine.
Deceiving your investors,
Julian,
is hardly a business model.
Whoever controls
the Permanence Code
controls the future.
We have to win.
[♪ tense music playing]
Look, I...
admire your vision.
Straighten up.
However, the board will only
stand behind you
for another six months...
if you're lucky.
But if it doesn't work...
all of this goes away,
darling.
Everything we have built
for the past 40 years.
What if I said
I had found a way?
[footsteps receding]
[gasping]
[panting]
[dings]
[grunts] Oh. I think this is
my 95th breakfast burrito,
and, honestly, can't get
enough. Isn't that wild?
Well...
Nice to see Tess
wasn't the only
obsessive one in the family.
"Yeah, Seth, you're right.
Sorry, I should pay
more attention to you."
"Oh, don't worry about it."
Okay. [scoffs]
[keyboard clacking]
-I'm sorry.
-Get out of here.
Look, three months in sub-zero
is a long time, I get it.
Yeah, and four days,
ten hours, 32 minutes.
Who's counting, really?
You know...
[computer beeping]
Hold on.
[Seth] What do you mean?
What?
[keyboard clacking]
[♪ victory jingle plays]
Seth.
-What, you found something?
-I think so.
[Seth] The line of code.
That's how he hid it,
it's two lines.
[Seth] Whoa.
That looks like
a double helix.
It is a double helix.
Tess would've loved this.
[Seth] Wait. Are you serious?
So no more
"29 minutes and out"?
If this is what I think it is,
it's the Permanence Code.
[whispers] Okay.
Encom offline trial 317a-1.
Permanence Code implemented.
Testing for asset stability
beyond current
29-minute barrier.
Go.
[breathing heavily]
-Ready when you are.
-Okay.
[beeping]
[machine humming]
[♪ energetic music plays]
It's all in the wrists, baby.
[exhales deeply]
[chuckles]
That never gets old.
[Eve] Trial commenced.
Twenty-nine minutes
and counting down.
[sighs]
[sighs] Let's see
if you last this time.
[Julian]
Ares is the ultimate soldier.
If by some miracle
he is struck down
on the battlefield,
I will simply
make you another.
[Julian, Ares]
Fully proprietary, 100%...
[Ares] ...expendable.
-Athena.
-[Athena] Welcome back, sir.
All units are online
and ready for inspection.
So how was it?
[Ares] It was interesting.
Different this time.
I met a mother and a son.
It was raining.
The condensed moisture
of the atmosphere
falling visibly
in separate drops.
I could almost feel it.
Feel? I don't understand.
[Eve on voicemail]
This is Eve.
Get sensible and text.
Hey, Eve. It's Erin. Got Ajay
for you again. Hit us back.
-[line beeps]
-Still straight to voicemail.
[scoffs]
CEO of a Fortune 500 company
and your phone's down
on our biggest night?
Goddamn it.
Where the hell are you, Eve?
[emcee]
All right, Paranoia-Con!
[crowd cheers]
In five, four,
three, two, one.
[timer beeping]
[exhales deeply, gasps]
Did we just do it?
Dude, it's still there!
Dude, we just changed
the world, man!
[echoing] You did it, Eve!
Oh, my God, you did it.
[Robin Roberts on TV]
Big news out of Encom tonight.
CEO Eve Kim will not attend
the highly anticipated
launch event
for the company's new game,
Space Paranoids: Panic City.
Kim, the visionary designer
behind the relaunch of
the blockbuster franchise...
Well, I spoke to several
of our board members,
and needless to say
they are impressed.
[TV continues, indistinct]
Julian.
-[Julian] Just carry on.
-Yes, sir.
What are you doing?
[Julian] Oh, just trying to
change the world, Mother.
What's going on?
You're hacking Encom?
Just a peek
over the garden wall.
No one will notice.
What makes you think
that Encom
is any closer to finding it?
Because I know who else
is looking for it, all right?
Who?
Eve Kim.
She's following
in her sister's footsteps.
She's after
the Permanence Code.
I can feel it.
So I'm gonna find her,
and when I do...
No, I don't like it.
It's too risky, Julian.
Oops.
[♪ intense music plays]
[slurps]
[Pete on PA]
Security breach in all zones.
[Ares breathes deeply]
Programs,
our directive is clear.
Penetrate the server core and
extract Eve Kim's user file.
[backstage AD]
Live in five, four, three...
[crowd cheering]
Space Paranoids fans,
are you ready?
[♪ "Paranoid" playing]
Put your hands together
for Encom CTO, Ajay Singh!
-It's cowboy time.
-Oh, no.
[Ajay] Whoo!
Nice to see you!
Hello.
Thank you.
What's up, Paranoia-Con?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Ares panting]
I'm going in.
[Ares groaning, grunting]
[Julian] I'm in.
I'm a genius! Who knew
you raised a genius, Mother?
I'm in!
In deep shit.
[sighs]
[Ares breathing deeply]
[alarm blaring]
Initiate containment protocols
and pull all network access.
We need a response now.
Initiate security protocol.
[Dr. Fei-Fei Li on video]
People are trusting
artificial intelligence
with their lives.
Are you comfortable with this?
Well, look.
For every doomsday scenario,
there's
a medical breakthrough,
scientific discovery.
So maybe what emerges from
the unknown isn't so scary.
What if its major malfunction
is just benevolence?
What is this? What's he doing?
But still, would you prefer
to talk to a real person?
Of course,
but what if that person
is no longer in your life?
No longer here? [echoing]
[computer hums]
[alarm blares]
[Ares breathing heavily]
I've got the file.
[Elisabeth] Congratulations.
Now get out of there
while you still can.
[♪ intense music plays]
[shouting]
Programs, we fight.
[breathes sharply]
[grunts]
-[Encom guard screams]
-[grunts]
[groans]
Yes!
Thank you so much.
What do Paranoiacs do?
[audience]
Grind you into dust!
[Caius groans]
[Ares] Caius.
He's dysfunctional. Leave him.
[Caius grunts, screams]
[Ares]
You're gonna make it, Caius.
Sometimes you have to
sacrifice your knight
to expose their queen.
[Caius panting]
[Ares, Athena scream]
...to debut the latest version
of Space Paranoids: Panic City
with the world.
-[fan A] What's up, bro?
-[fan B] What is that?
-[fan C] This is crazy.
-[fan D] Have you seen this?
[security] Mr. Singh,
you need to come with me.
This is
a technical difficulty.
-We'll be back.
-[security] This way, sir.
[fan E]
Everything's gone down.
[Julian Hologram]
Well done, Master Control.
Eve Kim's file acquired.
Objective achieved.
Sir, I'm curious
why the Program Caius
was not reconstituted.
[♪ sentimental music plays]
I'm curious
why you are curious.
Caius was dysfunctional,
so he was deleted.
Just like any program
that operates outside
their directive can be.
Do you understand?
Acknowledge, Master Control.
Of course.
We are 100% expendable.
New mission, Master Control.
Locate Eve Kim.
Yes, sir.
Seems like we had
a little cyber breach, Jules.
But then of course
you knew that.
It looks like
the whole world knows, buddy.
Might wanna stay off
the socials for a few days.
You wanna play games with me?
Let's play games, Julian.
I heard about your cute
little pitch to the board.
But you left off one
key detail from your deck.
Did you tell them
the shot clock expires
at 29 minutes?
Don't make me call The Journal
and tell them
you're making promises
you can't keep.
Promises?
What, you mean like the one
that your CEO
will be in office
running the company?
Something in the water
over there, Ajay?
I mean, first, wonder boy
Sam Flynn, now his successor.
Where is she, Ajay?
Do you even know where she is?
Maybe you're right.
Maybe Eve went nuts.
Maybe she went AWOL
and left the country,
or maybe...
she's holed up off the grid
looking for the same
thing you are.
And I know who my money's on.
You mean what's left of it
after tonight.
End of line!
[line beeps]
[sighs] I hate that man.
[Seth] Thank you so much.
You know,
I made those oranges.
It's a long story. [chuckles]
[Eve humming]
-[phone beeping]
-Stop, stop, stop.
[chuckles] What are you doing?
-1913 messages. Popular.
-[Eve] Wow.
Oh, it's Ajay.
Yeah, that's you.
-Ajay, are you there?
-[Ajay] Am I here?
A brute force attack
took down our servers
during our biggest
product launch in years.
Everything we've built
is melting down.
You need to get back here
right now.
I found it, Ajay. It's real.
Right where
Tess thought it would be.
Flynn had it all along.
Are you talking
about the Permanence Code?
Yeah. Four hours and counting.
Zero degradation,
no instability.
It's incredible.
Wait a second.
Did you say four hours?
-[Eve] Yeah, four hours.
-My God.
He must know, Evie.
- I just spoke to Dillinger.
-Wait.
-You just spoke to Dillinger?
-[Ajay] He's looking
for the code,
and he thinks you are too.
We gotta move on this.
Eve,
you've done a great thing.
Tess did a great thing.
I'm en route to Encom.
We'll secure the code,
I have it with me on a drive.
[computer chimes]
[♪ sentimental music plays]
[Eve on video]
We're relaunching Paranoia!
Boy, it's your birthday.
-[Eve] Yeah! Ajay.
-Boy, it's your birthday.
[man on video]
Yo, what's up, Eve?
You've got some news
for the freaks at home?
[Eve on video] Um, hi.
[Ares] "I am fearless,
and therefore powerful."
So, apparently we just sold
our ten millionth unit!
Evie , Space Paranoids.
Kevin Flynn,
wherever the hell he is,
has a big smile on his face.
Oh, you crushed it.
No. [chattering]
[both giggling]
♪ Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Tess ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
-[Eve breathing shakily]
-[heart monitor beeping]
[newscaster] Breaking news.
Encom's Head
of Special Projects,
Tess Kim, died today
after a long battle
with cancer.
Her sister, Eve Kim, could not
be reached for comment.
[♪ sentimental music playing]
[computer beeping]
[Ares gasps]
Permanence.
Checkmate.
And so our heroes
venture off into the night.
Nothing but
the clothes on their backs
and, well,
a six-million-dollar
particle laser
that creates organic material
out of nowhere,
which is kind of crazy, right?
Keep the equipment safe
and just... lay low.
-Okay?
-Yeah.
Hey.
We got this.
[engines revving]
[♪ ominous music playing]
[bell rings]
[technician A on radio]
Launch directive
on countdown one. Comm check.
[technician B] GNC
[technician A]
Printing in progress.
[technician B] Stage one.
Chamber pressure is nominal.
[technician C]
Envac engine chill has begun.
Stage one load is complete.
[announcement on PA]
Transfer complete.
[♪ electronic music playing]
[whirring]
You have 29 minutes
to bring me Eve Kim.
[engines revving]
[singer vocalizing]
[engine revs]
[police scanner]
Asset deployment confirmed.
Vehicles en route.
[Ares] Target identified.
Goddamn it. I'm awesome!
[Ares] Intercepting now.
[engines revving]
[tires squealing]
[Ares] Eyes on the target.
[police scanner]
Coordinating containment
for suspect fleeing eastbound.
[Eve] What?
[siren blaring]
[police officer on speaker]
You, on the motorcycle!
Pull over.
[both gasp]
[pedestrians shriek]
-[horns honking]
-[tires screeching]
[panting]
[Eve] Come on.
[groans]
[panting]
[light cycle clicks]
Where'd she go?
[screaming] Come on!
[panting] Okay.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
[whirring]
[♪ triumphant
electronic music plays]
[Eve] Oh, my God.
Come on. Come on.
-[exclaims]
-[yelps]
[screaming]
[panting]
What?
[Eve screaming, muffled]
[pants] Okay.
-[screams]
-[horn honking]
[breathing heavily]
Oh, my God. Okay. [shrieks]
Oh, my God! [screaming]
[♪ suspenseful music plays]
[exhales]
Prepare the particle laser.
Time to move to plan B.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
[Eve groans]
Yeah.
[♪ suspenseful music
continues]
Oh, yeah. You wanna play?
[gasping]
[grunts]
[panting]
[electricity pulsating]
[Ares grunting]
[grunts]
[footsteps approaching]
What are you?
I am Master Control.
[helicopter blades whirring]
What do you want?
I want the code.
Well...
It's gone.
[groaning]
No, it's not.
I have her in my sights.
Establishing connection
to the Grid now.
Ready to transfer
in T-minus 15 seconds.
You're... a program.
[grunting]
You're timing out.
[grunting continues]
[police officer]
Get on the ground!
[screaming]
[groans]
[Julian]
Transfer her into the Grid.
[groans]
[reporter on TV] I'm on
the ground in downtown.
And I can tell you,
this was no elaborate stunt.
- Three riders...
-What have you done?
How could you be so reckless?
[Julian] When the world sees
what I have created,
all will be forgiven.
Is that what you think?
You think that
you're in control of this?
You're not.
Believing we can
change the world
is what keeps
this company relevant.
But it's also what can burn it
to the ground.
And your job
is knowing the difference.
[Voice of the Grid] Transfer
of biological life-form
in progress.
Digital reconstruction
initiated.
[grid tech 1]
Twenty percent digitized.
Forty percent digitized.
Sixty-five percent digitized.
Ninety-five percent digitized.
[Voice of the Grid]
Digitization complete.
Run diagnostics
and scan for corruption.
[♪ sinister music plays]
[Voice of the Grid] Eve Kim
identity disk activated.
-[computer hums]
-[gasps]
Wow.
Where am I?
Dillinger Systems
Central Processing Unit.
Wait. What?
We have identified
the sequence.
The user possesses the code.
The code?
I don't have the code.
I destroyed the drive.
[Athena] Silence, user.
The code isn't only
on a drive.
The code is inside of you.
Whether you remember it
or not,
you've seen it
and that is enough.
Sir, her disk is showing
signs of instability.
Define instability.
Extraction of the code
may result in de-resolution
of the carrier.
[Athena]
The directive is clear.
Isolate the thread
and commence extraction.
-[grid tech 1] Copy.
-[weapons buzz]
Wait. No, no, no.
Stop.
Athena is correct.
There's only one user
whose directive we follow.
[computer chimes]
[computer beeping]
[Julian]
What will remain of the user
if she were to suffer
de-resolution?
Nothing, sir.
No trace of her existence
on the Grid?
None, sir.
Extract the code
and delete the carrier.
But, sir, extracting
the Permanence Code
would delete the carrier from
the Grid and from your world.
Once upon a time,
there was a weapon
and its name was Ares.
And Ares obeyed every command
of Julian Dillinger,
and Julian Dillinger
made a trillion dollars.
And wrote his name
on the face of time in blood.
Now, whatever PEBKAC error
is behind these feelings,
I'm going to find it
and rip it out of you.
Do I make myself clear?
[♪ tense music plays]
Perfectly.
Program dismissed.
The creature also said,
"I am fearless,
and therefore powerful."
[♪ dramatic music plays]
[Athena] Well?
[Ares] The user is indisposed.
Hold extraction
until further directive.
-Indisposed?
-[Ares] Correct.
Define indisposed.
He's stuck in traffic.
No, he's at the opera.
He's standing on
the top of Mount Fuji
in a pair of green socks
playing "Pistol Packin' Mama"
on the mandolin.
I gave you an order.
The creator is indisposed.
Hold extraction until
we receive further directive.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, sir.
Programs dismissed.
Can I trust you?
It's a complicated question.
How much time you got?
Sixty seconds. Answer now.
Your life cycle
depends upon it.
I don't have a life cycle.
Yes, you do.
For another 54 seconds.
Can I trust you?
Um, I'd like to think so,
but probably not.
Where is Master Control?
Sir, Master Control
is exhibiting
signs of malfunction.
Hmm.
Any threat to the directive
must be eliminated.
Extract the code
and delete them both.
-Do you understand?
-Hmm.
-[Ares] And Julian Dillinger?
-You can't trust him.
For him, everyone
and everything is expendable.
I miscalculated.
We have a new directive.
Athena, it doesn't have to
be like this.
Delete him!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[thuds, echoing]
[groans]
[all screaming]
[groans, panting]
[screams]
[gasping]
[♪ mysterious music plays]
[panting]
[light cycle hums]
[revving]
I'm okay. I'm okay.
[Athena] They're headed
towards the Transfer Portal.
We lost them in the Grid,
ma'am.
Preparing the drones.
Delete Ares, and bring
the user back to me.
[grid tech 1] Copy.
[drones hum]
What happened back there?
I disobeyed my directive.
Which was?
To retrieve the code
from your disk
and delete the carrier.
Dillinger told you
to delete me?
Hang on!
[Athena] Where are they?
[grid tech 2] Scanning
quadrants three and four.
[grid tech 1] Sector 18 clear.
[engine revving]
Where are we going?
[Ares] Transfer Portal.
It's the only way
out of the Grid.
You'll be reconstituted
in the real world
exactly as you were before,
hypothetically.
[chuckles]
-Hypothetically?
-Probably.
[grid tech 1]
We have movement in sector 72.
[grid tech 2]
Zeroing in on target.
Shut them down!
[Ares] You wanna get home,
I can help you.
But I need something
in return.
I told you
I don't have the code.
You found it once,
you can find it again.
So you can give it
to Dillinger?
Not for Dillinger.
For me.
Do we have a deal?
[♪ mysterious music plays]
So, do we have a deal?
Yes. Yes, I know
where to find the code.
Just get me out of here.
[grid tech 1] Target
approaching Transfer Portal
in 45 seconds.
[grid tech 2] Drones
malfunctioned and offline.
[screams]
[PA] Attention.
Please stand clear.
[grid tech 1]
Override not responding.
Transfer bay is online.
-[Elisabeth] What is it?
-[Julian] Who authorized this?
[Cross] Sir, this originated
inside the Grid.
Julian?
[grid tech 1] All agents
report to transfer bay floor
immediately.
[PA] Clear the area.
Get everybody out of here.
[PA] Unauthorized printing
in progress.
Clear the central area.
[technicians clamoring]
[PA] Transfer complete.
[Cross] Move in.
[bell ringing]
-[chokes]
-[gasps]
[grunts]
[timer beeping]
[Julian] Well, well, well.
Just got double-crossed
by my program.
It wants the Permanence Code
for itself.
Eve, is that the deal?
It gets you out of the Grid,
you turn Pinocchio
into a real boy?
Well, you're missing the part
where you're willing
to commit murder
for a piece of software.
[Julian] Is that what it said?
Twenty-eight minutes,
41 seconds.
Ares!
I do hope
this works out for you.
There's no second chances,
no do-overs.
These are the last 29 minutes
you'll ever have!
Better make it count!
[♪ tense music plays]
[grunting]
-[tires screech]
-[horn honks]
I should've majored
in English lit.
[lasers humming]
[exhales deeply]
[PA] Transfer complete.
[Julian] Your directive is
to find Eve Kim,
return her to the Grid and
get me the Permanence Code.
By any means necessary.
Do you understand
your directive,
Master Control?
At your command, sir.
Attagirl.
[♪ intense music plays]
Ticktock!
Oh!
Oh! [chuckles]
Whoo!
Now that is the coolest thing
I have ever seen.
[inhales deeply]
Do you know
who Kevin Flynn was?
Of course.
Visionary programmer,
pioneer of
The Digital Frontier .
Disappeared 1989.
I found the Permanence Code
on a backup of Flynn's server.
That server is at Encom's
office downtown.
But we can make it within...
Twenty-six minutes,
nine seconds.
Eve, your plan contains
two major flaws.
Okay.
One, Encom is 9.2 miles away,
given our present speed
and suboptimal
choice of vehicle...
Oh, my God.
Two, we're gonna need
a particle laser.
We need a phone.
[tires squeal]
[tires screech]
I cannot believe
I'm doing this.
Excuse me. Do you see this?
This is me.
If you let me use
your cell phone,
my assistant
will wire you $10,000.
I just need your phone.
[♪ rock music playing softly]
Seth, where are you?
[Seth] Eve,
whose phone is this?
Listen to me. I need you
at Encom in 15 minutes.
Hey, is everything okay?
Seth, bring
the particle laser.
-Encom, 15 minutes. Got it.
- [tires screech, horn honks]
[engine revs]
That's my car.
[Eve]
I'll wire you another 50K.
Hey, that's my car!
The Honda Civic 2.0
four-cylinder
with 138 horsepower.
Classic.
Hey! That's my car!
That's my car!
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[engine revving]
[chuckles] God.
[truck horn blares]
-Eve?
-Yeah?
I was thinking about the time
you told your sister
that you wished you never
relaunched Space Paranoids .
Then you went on
to say that...
Oh, my God. Of course.
You read all my texts.
Yeah. Yeah, I've read
them all. Every single one.
Wow.
Most of it was information
of a personal nature.
Some of it, highly personal.
And I just can't get enough.
What?
Depeche Mode. Number eight
on the UK singles chart, 1982.
I find their brand of
pithy, catchy,
timeless and true
'80s electropop
to be deeply invigorating.
[♪ "Just Can't Get Enough"
playing]
Sixteen minutes, 20 seconds.
[chuckles] Okay. So you like,
uh, '80s pop
and, uh, cyber-spying on me.
I was directed
to kill you, Eve.
Hacking seems pretty tame
by comparison.
[♪ "Just Can't Get Enough"
continues]
[engine revving]
-Oh, my God.
-For the record,
I don't think you have
anything to be ashamed of.
Space Paranoids
has entertained
hundreds of millions.
Plus, it's a pretty cool game.
Anyway, you told your sister
that designing games
left you feeling
hollow, broken.
Was it that your work
was about
entertainment and profits
and her work was about
improving the human condition?
Your texts suggest
a certain fixation
with not being able to live up
to her standards,
which must have
been complicated,
especially considering
she was the younger sister.
Okay. Watch it.
By the way, I don't think
you should quit.
What do you mean?
Your plan upon returning
from the mountains,
if I read you correctly,
was to hand over
the Permanence Code to Encom
and then let them figure out
what to do with it next, no?
[♪ sentimental music playing]
Yeah. Now I understand.
You completed her work
as a way to
stay connected to her.
Huh.
And now what?
Being human is hard.
The things that make life
great are the same things
that make it excruciating,
like love, loss.
You must miss her very much.
[tires screech]
[passerby] Hey, hey.
[person 1] What the hell?
[person 2] Whoa.
Check this guy out.
-Well, look who it is!
-Hi.
Glad you could join us,
Miss Kim.
People have been wondering
where you've been.
Long time no see. Bit of
a rush, so I'm just gonna...
-Eve.
-Mm-hmm?
You gotta bring your badge.
Okay, yeah, Jolene...
Hello, Jolene. Hi.
Got her badge right here.
Okay. His too?
Uh, no. He's not with us.
-Yes, he is.
[elevator chimes]
[♪ "Summer Breeze" plays]
Let's start literally
anywhere you'd like. Um...
This is my boyfriend, Ares.
No. Master Control
Security Program
from Dillinger's Grid.
Ares, Seth. Seth, Ares.
Oh, God.
Pleasure.
Hey, that's nice.
Um, so, Ares, like, as in,
the god of war, Ares?
Yeah.
Cool. You're Greek.
That's awesome.
So when you say that
he's the security program,
do you mean he's like...
-Yeah. He's not human.
-He's not human.
-Mm-hmm.
-Originated inside a GPU.
[chuckles] Okay. Is this
for the Christmas video?
[elevator chimes]
Three minutes
to de-resolution.
[Eve]
Can you work with that, Seth?
[Seth] Yeah.
Don't need help, guys.
Okay.
Oh, boy.
[Eve] So, this is where
I found the Permanence Code
on a backup of this server.
Talk about first gen.
Talk about a piece of garbage.
Am I right? [chuckles]
That was super insensitive
to your ancestors,
and I'm so sorry.
It's gonna take me
a few minutes to set this up.
No rush. Two minutes,
18 seconds.
[Eve] Soon as the laser's up,
we'll send you into the Grid.
Once you're in there, you'll
have to run your own search,
but believe me, the Permanence
Code is in there.
So what should I expect?
Uh, if I were to guess?
Think '80s.
'80s.
I like the '80s.
One minute, 31 seconds.
[Seth] Okay. Come on.
[Seth] Please, help me.
Okay, all set.
Adapters.
[laser beeping]
[Eve]
Once you locate the code,
get to the portal
and we'll bring you out.
I'll activate it
from the outside.
Can I trust you?
I'd like to think so,
-but probably not.
-Probably not.
Yeah.
Well, it's a good thing
we don't have trust issues
because if we did,
I could imagine that--
I could pull the plug
and leave you in a Grid less
complex than my smartphone
for all eternity.
The thought had
crossed my mind.
Mine too.
Oh, mine three.
Sorry. Just...
Well, here goes nothing.
Or here goes something.
You're right.
I do miss her.
All the time.
[jump jet rumbling]
Athena. She's here.
Whoa. What is that?
Athena.
Wait. Who?
Seth, the laser. The laser!
Okay, initiating systems now.
Connecting to the Flynn Grid.
[Seth] Firing up the laser.
Wait, what's she doing?
She's waiting for me
to time out...
...and then she'll come
for you.
[Eve]
We're almost there. Get ready.
[Seth] Come on.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
[Eve] Ares, move
in front of the laser.
[Seth] Okay. We're ready.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Change of plans.
-No, no, no!
-[Seth] No, wait!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[♪ inspirational music
playing]
Well, that actually worked.
[chuckles]
-He's inside.
-Great.
Move!
[♪ intense music plays]
[breathing heavily]
[debris clattering]
Eve.
[yelps]
[Athena]
Time to get back to the Grid.
Leave her alone!
You're very persistent, user.
[laser hums]
[water splashing]
[screaming]
[sobbing]
[Seth groans]
[groans]
What?
Hi.
Did we win?
-She'll be back.
-[coughs]
Ares.
He can't get out.
The '80s.
[electrical whirring]
[♪ mysterious music playing]
Binary digit.
-You're a Bit.
- Yes.
I'm looking for something.
Can you help me find it?
Yes, yes, yes.
[electronic beeping]
[♪ majestic music plays]
[whirring]
Classic.
I'm surrounded by
the wide-scale destruction
caused by tonight's
brazen attack
that left local residents
stunned.
There is speculation that
Dillinger Systems
had something to do
with the event,
and authorities have
remained tight-lipped.
-[alarm ringing]
- [newscaster] Citizens
and authorities alike
want to know...
was this a coordinated attack
or technology run amok?
[Julian sighs] What now?
[alarm continues]
[gasps]
What is this?
Where's my code?
Hey!
What are you doing?
Who gave you this directive?
You did, sir.
What is this?
[computer voice] Warning.
No, no, no.
This is too big, Athena.
Too big!
[Elisabeth] Julian!
You're done.
The board is moving
as we speak
to strip you of your title,
and I'm reassuming control
of the company.
No, you can't do that.
Can't do that!
[Elisabeth] Yes, I can.
This is not going any further.
You can't...
My first order of business
is shutting down
-The Permanence Project.
-No, no, no. Mom, no!
[grunts, gasps]
-[gasping]
-Don't be afraid.
We gave a thousand lives
for the Grid.
You only have to give one.
[echoing] No, no, no.
Mom!
Impediment eliminated.
What did you do?
I am fulfilling my directive.
Capture Eve Kim.
Return her to the Grid
by any means necessary.
Scanning
for further impediments.
[Elisabeth groaning]
[computer voice]
Please keep clear.
Hang on, Mom. Hang on.
[Elisabeth groans]
No!
[electronic beep]
[breathes deeply]
[whooshing sound]
[chuckles]
[whirring]
Flynn.
Greetings, program.
[♪ ominous music playing]
[people clamoring]
Oh, God. Not good.
[reporter]
There are multiple reports
of fire and destruction
on the upper levels...
Um, Eve?
What the hell happened
to our office?
Ajay, look, there's no time.
The Dillingers transported me
inside their server
by reversing the direction
of a particle laser.
-Not this one. Theirs.
-That's impossible.
No. A scary lady did it, man.
She threw me... It was wild.
I saw a complex world
where packets of energy
move as vehicles
that trail by lines of light.
And-And programs
take on human form.
I met the most advanced AI
known to mankind.
His name is Ares.
Like the god of war, but he's
actually a super nice guy.
-Sorry.
-Right now,
Ares is inside
Flynn's original server.
He's looking
for the Permanence Code.
I have to bring him back here,
and I'm not going to be able
to do that
until we fix this laser.
I don't understand.
Are you alive?
I exist in this moment
because you do.
A reflection of your presence.
What's your story?
I'm Ares, Master Control of
the Dillinger Security Grid.
Dillinger?
Hmm.
Well, we both know
you can't get here from there.
Been someplace else
in between?
What did you make of it
out there?
It's hard to put
in a nutshell.
[chuckles]
You can say that again.
It's hard to put
in a nutshell.
[laughs]
Ah, classic. Humor, man.
Oh.
What are you looking for?
Permanence.
The Permanence Code,
to be exact.
Strange things have
been happening.
I questioned my directive.
I disobeyed my directive.
Mmm.
A malfunctioning program
who wants to live.
Really?
What makes you think
I should help you?
No, it's not about me.
Not anymore.
I have a friend in danger,
and she needs my help.
[Flynn chuckles]
Fascinating.
Hey, Ajay, can you send
the prompt, please?
[Ajay] Sure, yeah.
-Uh, hey, Eve.
-Not now, Seth.
Okay. Hey, are you sure?
Because that looks like
an actual Recognizer
flying towards us.
[♪ tense music playing]
What in God's name is that?
It's Athena.
She's back.
As long as the Dillinger
Network is online,
she'll keep coming.
If she gets me,
she gets the Permanence Code.
The laser. Athena's laser!
The Dillingers run a wireless
direct link protocol,
so let's use
what's left of the laser
to ping the network
and trace a path home.
Once you have a connection,
then you can nuke
the whole Dillinger Grid.
And that's the only way
to stop her for good.
Eve, what are you
talking about?
She's right there.
-I gotta go.
-[Ajay] Wait, what?
I'll keep her away
for as long as I can.
-What?
-I'm gonna buy you some time.
-Eve...
-You guys got this.
-[panting]
-[siren wailing]
[Ares] You're right.
I think there is
something wrong with me.
[Flynn] Or maybe there's
something right with you.
Well, maybe you're
just learning.
That's what we all
ought to be doing.
Back in the day,
when tech was young,
I'd think,
"Damn, we're moving fast."
[sighs] You move fast,
you leave stuff behind.
How many people
born in this century
have even heard of Mozart?
I like Mozart.
[chuckles]
Oh?
That said, if I'm being
honest, I prefer Depeche Mode.
[chuckles]
Really? Why is that?
I know one is considered
the greatest composer
in the history
of Western civilization,
the other a synth pop band
from the '80s,
but I find their balance
of technological exploration
and pop hooks combined with...
Uh, com-- Uh...
combined with, uh...
What's wrong?
I-I can't put my love
of Depeche Mode into words.
It's just a...
Hmm? A what?
A feeling.
[chuckles]
Very good.
Very good, man.
[sniffling]
[gasping] You...
You did this.
[reporter]
And tonight, as military...
[Ajay] Impressive.
Fully segmented
zero trust architecture.
Built to be
totally impregnable
to vertical, lateral
or hybrid attacks.
Damn it.
Can't get a connection, dude.
No luck here either.
[people clamoring]
[officer]
Please, evacuate the area.
[clamoring continues]
[Recognizer whirring]
What is that thing?
-Bring in SWAT!
-Requesting backup.
[♪ ominous music plays]
[Seth] Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
[clamoring]
Come on. A little closer.
[panting]
[pilot 1] Viper-1 to base.
Tally on hostile.
Confirmed visual ID.
Engaging Fox-2. Missile away.
[alarm beeping]
[pilot 2] Splash negative.
Missile intercepted.
Be advised,
enemy fighter escorts inbound
and moving fast.
[commander] Copy, Raven-1.
Assess and report
threat posture.
[pilot 2] Viper-1,
tally multiple bandits.
Hostile intent confirmed.
Mayday. Mayday. I'm hit!
Viper-1. Punching out.
[panting]
Uh, guys? Guys.
Oh, my God.
There's hundreds of 'em.
They're going after Eve.
If we can't access
the Dillinger server,
there's gonna be
nothing left to save.
[♪ intense music plays]
[pilot 2]
Base, this is Raven-1.
Enemy aircraft engaging.
I'm defensive.
Multiple bandits. Redirecting
to primary target.
I'm hit! Punching out.
[gasps, pants]
[grunts]
[♪ gentle electronic
music plays]
[whirring]
Ready?
Hope you are, man,
'cause there's no going back.
Permanence.
Funny.
When I found it,
that's what I called it.
I know better now.
Ought to be called
the Impermanence Code.
The back door to my old lab.
One go-around.
That's all you've got.
One...
is all I want.
Love that!
You keep surprising me!
[groans]
We'll do this
from the ground then.
[laser powering up]
[gasps, pants]
[engines roaring]
...and there are reports that
a civilian may be onboard,
making this
a possible hostage scenario.
[Seth] Athena.
She must've gotten Eve.
[reporter]
...into the mountains.
[officer] Hey, hey, hey!
[tires screech]
[gasps]
[Athena] Soon we'll be back
on the Grid.
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[screams]
[horns blare]
[reporter] General, thank you
for taking the time...
-[distorted beeping]
-...to speak with us tonight.
Hey, Erin. Seth.
Stop the clock.
No way. You're in?
There's a reason why I have
the corner office, my man.
[groaning softly]
Hey.
[Eve coughs]
You came back.
How did you...
Let's just say I had
a little help from a friend.
[chuckles]
Wait, the Dillinger Grid...
Ajay and Seth, they...
[rumbling]
[♪ tense music playing]
-Go.
-No.
Ares!
What have you done?
You're out of time, Athena.
And you're out of lives.
I'll kill you
and come back for her.
[mechanical whirring]
It's you she wants.
If she gets the code,
she can't be stopped.
You had everything.
-Go.
-No.
The most advanced,
the most powerful,
and you gave it away.
For her?
Go!
This is the end for you.
[♪ exciting music playing]
[grunting]
Payload ready for transfer.
Shipping it.
Let's hope Eve was right.
[alarm blaring]
[computer voice] Alert.
Unknown file incoming.
[groaning]
In pursuit of this life
for yourself,
did you once consider
what that meant for the Grid?
[shouts]
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[Athena shouts]
We were given an order.
It is our purpose.
[groaning]
It's not our purpose.
It's our programming.
Our purpose is yet
to be determined.
-[electronic whirring]
-[Ares grunting]
[all chuckle, sigh]
It's over.
And there's no coming back.
No.
Not this time.
They did it.
[Seth] Oh, my...
[all cheering]
[gasping]
I followed my directive.
I know.
And now...
what is yours?
I'm not sure.
-I guess we'll see.
-[beeping]
[beeping intensifies]
[wheezes]
[reporter]
Dillinger Systems is
under intense scrutiny tonight
as speculation grows around
its potential involvement
in the series
of devastating attacks
that have rocked the city.
Federal authorities
have confirmed
an active investigation into
the company's recent activity,
and many are pointing directly
at CEO Julian Dillinger.
Agents have been deployed
to question the CEO
as well as his mother,
and to locate board members
who will be questioned
on the situation.
Meanwhile,
the city remains in disarray.
Emergency services
are overwhelmed,
while entire neighborhoods
are dealing with
-the wide-scale destruction.
- [police sirens wailing]
[♪ tense music playing]
[exhales sharply]
[grunts]
[officer] Julian Dillinger,
this is the police.
We have you surrounded.
Open the door and come out
with your hands up.
[exhales sharply]
[grunts] Come on.
[gasps]
[officers] Breach!
Police!
Stay where you are!
[officer 1 on radio]
Maintain visuals on all exits.
[officer 2] Charlie-9,
we're at last field location.
Last field location.
Yellow-6, out front.
Let's move. Let's move.
[Eve] Ow.
[Ares] Are you good?
Oh, I think
I broke a rib. [groans]
[both sigh]
[chuckles]
You still gonna quit your job?
No, I'm not
gonna quit anything.
Good.
I have some ideas.
Oh, yeah? Nice.
Well, the world
needs you, Eve.
The Grid needs you.
[chuckles]
Yeah. It's funny, permanence.
A wise man once told me
it should have been called
the "Impermanence Code."
I guess that's
the thing about life.
There's nothing
quite permanent about it.
No.
No, there isn't.
Yeah.
[sirens wailing in distance]
[Eve groans]
So where are you gonna go?
I have some ideas.
Mmm.
[sirens continue]
[police chatter
on loudspeaker]
[narrator] Under the
leadership of CEO Eve Kim,
Encom is
transforming industries...
...and shaping lives in ways
once thought impossible.
Thanks to the discovery
of the Permanence Code,
the company has made
revolutionary advances
growing crops
in climate-vulnerable regions,
developing drugs for
treatment-resistant cancers,
and accelerating
the development
of alternative fuels.
Encom is committed
to exploring
new digital frontiers,
driving progress
at the intersection
of technology and life itself
to improve
the human condition.
In fact, innovation has always
been at the heart of Encom.
In the 1980s,
visionary Kevin Flynn imagined
a future beyond gaming,
a bold leap
into new digital frontiers.
Today, that vision
is a reality.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Postcard?
Who sends a postcard?
Don't know. Didn't read it.
[Ares] Dear Eve,
since I last saw you,
I've been living
what they call "off-grid."
Pun intended.
In my travels,
I've seen incredible things.
Despite its wonder and beauty,
I've come to realize
that life is...
Well, it's hard
to put in a nutshell.
Some days,
I find myself wondering
where we'll be
a hundred years from now...
...and how others like me
might fit into that future.
I feel like I might not be
alone with these questions.
For now,
I don't think the world
is quite ready to meet me,
but I am meeting the world.
And so, when that
introduction finally comes,
as a good friend of mine
once said,
"Maybe what emerges
from the unknown
won't be so scary after all."
Until we meet again,
your friend, Ares.
[sighs]
[♪ "As Alive As You Need Me
To Be" playing]
[electricity crackling]
[grunting]
[coughs, grunts]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[program voice echoing]
Sark...
-[electricity pulsating]
-[screams]
[♪ gentle music playing]